Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Student Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of History, student papers
1892-1926
SC0556
Stanford University. Department of History.
4 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer.
Information about Access
None.
Scope and Content
This collection contains class notes, research papers, and a few senior theses from history classes at Stanford University, 1892-1903 with a few from 1907-08 and 1925-26. Classes were in ancient, European, and American history.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged alphabetically by student author. For those women students who later married, their married name is included in paratheses after their maiden name.
Access Terms
Campbell, W. E., (William Edward), 1875-; Carlsmith, Nelle Wood.; Clark, Walter.; Fraser, Alfred P.; Johnson, John Everett.; Leventritt, Mortimer Clifford.; McGregor, Richard C., (Richard Crittenden), 1871-1936.; Rose, Walter Malins,, 1872-1908.; Schulte, William.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Students.;; Young, Belle McMurtry.; History--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Ayer, Helen. The Character and Policy of Robespierre., 1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bates, Callie H. The Life of Martin Luther up to the Diet of Worms. History 12, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bell, James W. Constitution of Venice. History 2, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bernhard, Joseph P. Greek and Roman Oratory., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bernhard, Joseph P. History of the Elective Franchise in New England., 1895 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bernhard, Joseph P. The Provincial Government of Asia., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Boston, William Morten. The Powers of the States and the United States in Relation to Civil Rights Under the 14th Amendment. History 15, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Braly, Bertha H. Marie Antoinette and her Influence on the French Revolution. History 11, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Braly, Bertha H. Savonarola and the Renaissance. History 6, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Brown, Ora L. The Renaissance in Rome. History 6, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brown, David E. Marco Polo and Geographical Knowledge of the Middle Ages. History 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Brown, David E. Roman Roads, Bridges Fortifications., undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bullock, Bertram N. A History of Slavery in Virginia, 1619-1800., 1895 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Campbell, William E. The Development of the Constitution as Influenced by the Decisions of Chief Justice Marshall., 1896 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Chamberlain, Robert S. Argentina and the War. History 231, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chamberlain, W. P. Lafayette and the French Revolution., 1894 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Chamberlain, W. P. Roman Bookmaking., undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Chandler, Leo St. Clair. The Transvaal Question., undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Chapman, Elizabeth (Mrs. Robert L'Amy Donald). The Rise of the Mendicant Orders., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Clark, Walter. History of the Controversies Relating to the Fisheries and the Fur Seal Industries of the United States., 1899 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Cobert, Albert. Erasmus and the Reformation. History 12, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Conneau, Myrtie (Mrs. William H. Langdon). The First meeting of the Indians and Whites on the Pacific Coast. History 26, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Conneau, Myrtie (Mrs. William H. Langdon). Lorenzo Ghiberti., undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Conneau, Myrtie (Mrs. William H. Langdon). The Moral and Religious Reforms of Charles the Great., undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Cook, Blanche A. (Mrs. William Henry Crothers). Literary Contest Between Christianity and Heathenism in the Second and Third Centuries. History 1, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Cory, Mabel H. Ethical Significance of Machiavelli as a Political Thinker. History 6, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Cory, Mabel H. The Peasant Revolt of 1381., 1894 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Cory, Mabel H. Review of Dumont's Recollections of Mirabeau. History 20, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Cox, Mabel L. Erasmus as a Humanist. History 12, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Crider, W. C. Notes from unspecified class, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Cummings, Frank J. Aaron Burr and the Conspiracy of 1806. History 8, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Darly, Marian. Alexander the Sixth., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Davis, Grace M. The Ecclesiastical Aspects of the Early Carolingian Period. History 12, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Davis, Grace M. Notes from History 3b, spring, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Deasy, Michael. Life of Dante., 1897 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Doty, Frank C. Import and Export Duties of England during the Middle Ages., 1895 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Earl, Clara. Marie Antoinette, Her Life and Her Influence upon the French Revolution., undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Earl, Clara E (Mrs. James F. Lanagan). The Presidential Administration of John Tyler. History 15, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Everett, Elizabeth A. [The University in France]., undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Everett, Ralph W. Naples from 1350 to 1500 AD. History 6a, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Faris, Wallace S. The Royal Family in the French Revolution., 1892 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Fickes, Helen E. (Mrs. L. H. McKinnie). Relations with the Indians in Virginia in the Seventeenth Century. History 7, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Foster, Mary C. (Mrs. Gerald Riotte). Athenian Festivals. History 1, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Fowler, William Atwater. Alfred, a Thesis., undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Fowler, William Atwater. The Rise and Spread of Mohammedanism., undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Francis, George H. A Thesis on the Early Sculpture of the Fifteenth Century., 1898 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Fraser, Alfred P. Description of a Roman Banquet., undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Fraser, Alfred. P. Dustan., undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Fraser, Alfred. P. The Knights Templars., undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Glover, Irma A. Madame Roland., 1894 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Hale, Alice Staniford. The Surprise of Amiens. History 10B, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Hammerson, Alice L. (Mrs. Syms Gillogley). Botticelli. History 6a, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Hanna, Alberta. Lecture and Reading Notes from History 3b, Medieval History, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Hansen, Edna M. The Cluniac Reform and its Relation to the Papacy. History 12, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Harkins, Mary S. B. (Mrs. Gilbert H. Johnson). A special Report on Domenico Ghirlandajo 1449-c.1498; His Life and His Works. History 6a, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Haskell, Jessie J. (Mrs. William M. Parkin). Life and Works of Lorenzo Ghiberti. History 2, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Hazzard, William C. Financial Causes of the French Revolution., undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Hearne, Virginia. (Mrs. Wilbur C. McNeil). The French Church in the Eighteenth Century. History 13, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Horr, Marrion Augusta. (Mrs. Augustine Jones). Colonial Sumptuary Laws. History 14, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Howard, Delle. (Mrs. Roy E. Dickerson). The Origin of the Ballot and a Brief History of elections in Colonial New England. History 7, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Howse, Emma. The Danes Before Canute. History 10, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Howse, Emma. Saracen Civilization in Spain. History 2, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Johnson, John Everett. Florence 1300-1500. History 6a, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Kidwell, Minna A. (Mrs. Minna K. Hotchkiss). Knights Templar. History 2, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- King, Anna R. (Mrs. Robert E. Granlees). Lotteries in Colonial New England. History 7, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Kip, Irving. Jamaica Notes., 1896 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Klink, Carol (Mrs. Jack S. Claussen). Chile and the Great War. History 138, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Leventritt, Mortimer C. Donatello and His Works. History 6, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Longley, John A. Excommunication and Interdict., undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Lyman, Chester L. Was Barras Venal? History 31, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Lyman, Maud L. Savonarola and the Renaissance. History 6a, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Magee, E. Delos. Life and Policy of Robespierre., 1894 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Martin, Anna H. Poverty and Pauperism Under the Roman Republic. History 1, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Matthews, Helen L. Abelard and the University of Paris. History 25, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Matthews, Helen L. Influence of Benjamin Franklin on the French Revolution. History 11, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Matthews, Helen L. The Senate under the Empire. History 2, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- McFadden, Thomas L. Financial Causes of the French Revolution., 1899 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- McGregor, Richard. Abailard and Heloissa. History 6, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- McKibben, Maud (Mrs. Frederick J. Fraser). Stewart's Letters of the Carlemont Collection as a Source., 1904 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- McMurtry, Belle Stuart (Mrs. William R. K. Young). Marie Antoinette and the French Revolution., 1899 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Meyer, Abe Lucien. Character and Statesmanship of Danton., undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Miller, Charles W. John Marshall; His Interpretation of the Constitution. History 8, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Moulton, H. B. Alienation in Mortmain., 1893 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Mourot, Louise A. Florence., undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Mullins, Joanna M. (Mrs. Andrew E. Donovan). Giovani Villani. History 6, 1900 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Mullins, Joanna M. (Mrs. Andrew E. Donovan). Plagues, Pestilences, Famines and Other Calamities in Their Influence on Public Affairs., 1897 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Newberg, Lucile J. Joan of Arc., undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Park, Harriet (Mrs. Harry P. Cramer). Class notes., undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Patterson, Frances D. History of the Development of the Post Office in America. History 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Perrin, Arch. Correggio., 1902 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Peterson, Ida Mae (Mrs. Joseph H. Johnson). Critical Examination of a Letter Announcing the Death of Gustavus Adolphus in the Battle of Lutzen. History 5, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Peterson, Ida Mae (Mrs. Joseph H. Johnson). Famines Plagues and Other Calamities In Their Effect on the Public. History 2, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Reynolds, Marian F. Michel Angelo., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Rider, William Leslie. The American Revolutionary Controversy prior to the Reign of George the Third. History 8, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Roesner, Gwendolen. Reading Notes for History 3b, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Rose, Walter M. The Assize of Clarendon., 1894-95 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Rose, Walter M. History of French Spoliations Committed Prior to 1800., 1893 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Rose, Walter M. A Review of Burke's Reflections on the French Revolution., 1894 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Rose, Walter M. Voyages and Travels of Marco Polo. History 2, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Rosendale, Charles. The Church in the Kingdom of Charlemagne. History 5, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Rosendale, Charles. The Girondists: Principals and Policy., 1894 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Rosendale, Charles. Our Naval Policy to 1816., 1895 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Russell, Isaac. Andrea Del Sarto., 1902 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Schleiden, John Hidalgo. Imperial Taxation. History 1, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Schneider, Frederick Arthur, Jr. Organization and Discipline of the Jesuits., 1899 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Schulte, William H. G. An Examination of the Mark Theory with Special Relations to the Works of Caesar and Tacitus., 1895 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Selby, Georgia A. (Mrs. Roy D. Davis). The Origin and Development of the American Protective Tariff 1789-1820. History 8, 1897 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Sisson, Louis Eugene. Giorgione., undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Stager, Cora Elizabeth. Maximilian I of Germany. History 12a, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Suhr, Rebecca S. (Mrs. Rutledge M. Woodward). The Judicial Administration of the Roman Provinces. History 2, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Swanson, Tillie Lucretia (Mrs. Arthur E. Cornelius). Development of International Postal Facilities of the United States., 1899 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Taylor, Ruth. Bacon's Rebellion. History 7, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Thomas [?], Emily T. Abelard and Heloise., undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Tompkins, Mrs. C. Torr. Survival and Significance of Well-worship in England. History 12, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Traphagen, K. Ethel. The Life and Works of Tiziano da Vecelli., 1902 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Tripp, L. Mae (Mrs. George A. Waterman). Letters of Rev. John Nixon to Miss Mary Bacon. History 10, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Van Norden, Ottomar H. More's Utopia and the Social Problem in England. Thesis for B.A., 1899 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Victor, Royall C. The Emancipation of the Russian Peasantry., 1899 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Victor, Royall Charles. Examination of the Grievances Leading to Secession. History 15, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Walker, Charles A. Eadward the Confessor., undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Walker, Charles A. Relations between Modern Labor Organizations and Early Craft Gilds [sic]., 1895 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Walker, Charles A. Trial by Jury., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Watson, Arthur Barry. The Greek Theatre. History 1, 1901 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Wight, John K. The Origin and Character of the Ordinance of 1787., undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Wigle, Keith. Translation from Lavisse Fr Rambaud., undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Willis, Helen (Mrs. William McKay). [Life of Francis]., undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Wisely, Kathryn Gross. The Ratification of the Federal Constitution in Massachusetts. History 186, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Wood, Jessie P. The Life of Saint Anselm., undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Wood, Jessie P. The Relation of the State to the Papacy in the Fourteenth Century., undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Wood, Lee A. Tintoretto., undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Wood, Nelle (Mrs. Carl S. Carlsmith). Education in the Middle Ages., undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Wood, Nelle (Mrs. Carl S. Carlsmith). Persecutions of the Early Quakers in America., undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Wood, Nelle (Mrs. Carl S. Carlsmith). A Study of the Cahiers of the French Revolution., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Yoder, Minnie B. (Mrs. Howard C. Lucas). Marie Antoinette and Her Influence on the French Revolution., 1894 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Young, William George. Moorish Architecture (711-1492). History 2, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Zilisch, Ina. Translations of Assmann's Geschichte des Mittelalters and Destruction de l'Empire Carolingien., undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Zschokke, Theodore C. The Continental Army. History 8, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Unidentified. Notes on Crimean War (History 29?)., undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Unidentified. The Influence of the Jesuits on the French Revolution., 1896 (Box 8, Folder 22)